A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Special Events and Activities, Anti-Vivisection Activities FA142
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Anti-vivisection Activities, 1908-1911; 1
  - Anti-Vivisection correspondence, 1930-1938; In 1 - 5" letter and 1 - 21/2" letter size boxes. GL 9/86
    - Goetsch, Emil (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Gruenberg, Benjamin C. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Hartwell, John A. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Hauenstein, Barton F. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Heberle, Margaret A. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Hill, A.V. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Hofstadter, Samuel H. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Holloway, J.W. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Hygeia (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Irving, Peter (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Ivy, A.C. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - James, Henry (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Jobling, James W. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Jones, F.S. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Journal of the American Medical Association (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Jung, Frederic T. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Kleiner, Israel S. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Kramer, Hyman L. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Kramer, H. Louis (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Kramer, Sidney (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Kramer, S.D. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Lambert, Samuel W. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Lamont, Wm. J. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Lee, Frederic S. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Lee, Ivy Mr. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Livermore, Shaw Mrs. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Lawrence, Joseph S., 1931-1937 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Martin, Franklin N. (Box 17, Folder 15)
      Includes typescript drafts of Rous paragraph on animal experimentation for American College of Surgeons publication "Animal Experimentation. Its Importance and Value to Scientific Medicine."
    - xf Medical Society of State of New York (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Middlekauff, Lorene Y. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Myers, J.A. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Morton,John J., 1932-1936 1938 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Ordway, Thomas (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Park, William H. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Parran, Thomas (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Rappleye, Willard C. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Reed, C.I. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Rigney, Ella H. Mrs. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Robertson, Albert D. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Robinson, G. Canby (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Robinson, James R., 1931-1933 1935 1937 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Schroeder, C.R. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Smith, E.B. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - re Shelling, David H. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Smith, Theobald (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Stockard, C.R. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sweet, J.E. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Swift, Homer F. re Senator and Mrs. Bert Lord medical report (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Sondern, Frederic H., 1931-1934 1937-1938 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Trask, L.M.D. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - van Beuren, Frederick T. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Wadsworth, Augustus B. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Welling, Richard (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Includes 1932 June 3 Carrel / Flexner correspondence.
    - Whipple, Allan (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Whipple, George (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Whitley, Jas. L. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Williams, H.B. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Williams, Linsly (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Wolf, Robert (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Woodward, William C. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Wyckoff, John (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Antivivisection correspondence (Box 18, Folder 3)
    [Typed and some handwritten list of names].
  - Animal Experimental Literature, 1908-1914 1920 1922-1924 1926 1945-1946; In 3 - 5" letter size boxes GL 9/86., Extra copies of printed material
    Arrangement: Articles by Simon Flexner and J.D. Greene, and then in alphabetical order by institution / publication.
    - Flexner, Simon. "A Refutation", New York Times, (of the So Called "Affidavits Concerning the Atrocities of Vivisection"), 1910 January 17 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Greene, J.D. "Arguments Against the Bayne Bill (310 Int.) for the Appointment of a Commission to Investigate Alleged Abuses of Vivisection", 1911 March 23 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - American Medical Association (AMA). Defense of Research Pamphlets #1-10, 1910-1911 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - AMA. Defense of Research Pamphlets #11-19, lacking 20, 1910-1911 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - AMA. Defense of Research Pamphlets #21-27, 1911-1914 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Boston Medical and Surgical Journal, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Collier's, 1922 October 14 1922 October 28 1924 November 8 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Friends of Medical Progress, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Friends of Medical Research, circa 1945 (date from original carton of extra copies) (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Georgetown University School of Medicine, GL 9/86 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
      - A course of lectures on animal experimentation, 1920 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - A Vindication of Vivisection. First edition, 1920 March 28-May 16 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - A supplement to a course of lectures on animal experimentation: Prominent Clergymen's Endorsement of Vivisection, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - A course of lectures on animal experimentation in 1920. Second edition published in 1923, 1920 1923 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Harper's Monthly, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Harper's Weekly, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Journal of the American Medical Association (JAMA), 1908 1923 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Includes 1908 editorials from JAMA and article by W.B. Cannon and in 1923 article by A.S. Loevenhart.
    - Medical Society of the State of New York, 1908-1909 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Issued under the auspices of the Committee on Experimental Medicine of.
    - Medical Society of the State of New York, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Medical Society of the State of New York, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Munsey Magazine, 1911 October (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Pageant, 1945 December (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Research Defense Society, 1909-1910 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Research Defense Society, 1920 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Survey Graphic, 1925 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Woman's Home Companion, 1926 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - World's Work, 1914 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Vivisection Reform Society, 1909 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Pamphlet - Walter B. Cannon and Cecil K. Drinker, The Dog's Gift to the Relief of Suffering (reprinted from the New England Journal of Medicine 1932) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Pamphlet - Why Animal Experimentation is Necessary for the General Welfare (published by the Medical Society of the State of New York 1932) (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook with newspaper clippings, circa 1909-1934 1948; 1948 (Box 22)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original document is Closed. Researchers should access the photocopy available in Box 22.
  - Scrapbook photocopy, circa 1909-1934 1948; 1948 (Box 23)
  - New York Supreme Court. Harry Moran against David H. Shelling, 1927; 1 bound volume
    Photostatic copy of testimony and Record of Appeal in 1927. Complaint by Harry Moran, an agent for the Humane Society of New York against David H. Shelling re torturing a dog.
    General note
    7